Reza Soleimani

Front-End Developer

PROFILE SUMMARY

An Architect and Designer turned into a Developer. I bring a unique Front-End Development skillset combined with my background in Architecture and UX/UI Design. I have experience developing responsive, user-friendly and accessible web applications using Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Firebase. I also created visual designs, prototypes and wireframes using Figma, Sketch and other tools. I am a creative person focused on delivering a seamless user experience.

PROJECTS

Binge Fest / API, React, JavaScript, Firebase, HTML and CSS December 2020 - During Bootcamp

- Binge Fest provides the user with TV show choices based on genre selection and restaurant choices based on location.
- It uses three APIs (Google Map, Yelp and Open Movie Database) and Firebase to save this information.

So Serious! / jQuery, Sass, CSS and HTML

November 2020 - During Bootcamp

- So Serious is a card game. The user can play until the joker card shows up.
- There is also a Batman Mode where the game's rules change, and users need to the first joker for their first card.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer / Freelance

April 2020 - September 2020, Toronto

 Contributed to COVID-19 initiatives and related products by conducting user research, usability tests, creating user flows, wireframes and high-fidelity mockups.

Architectural Designer

Eomac Ltd. / April 2019 - March 2020, Toronto
Canamould Extrusions Inc. / July 2016 - April 2019, Toronto
Penegal Trim & Supply Ltd. / October 2014 - July 2016, Toronto
Solution Build Group Inc. / May 2014 - October 2014, Toronto

- Collaborated with the design and technical teams to develop concepts, sketches and drawings of the products using AutoCAD, Revit, Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Assisted various clients, received their feedback and advised them
 of appropriate options to achieve their design goals.

www.rezasoleimani.ca github.com/rezaska reza.soleimani.ka@gmail.com 416.832.2825

SKILLS

Web Development: JavaScript, jQuery, React, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS/SASS, Firebase, Node.js, API, Git.

UX/UI Design: Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Additional: AutoCAD, 3D Max, Revit.

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp / Juno College
(formerly HackerYou)
September 2020 - January 2021

Eng. Software Skills Enhancement / Humber College

January 2015 - April 2015, Toronto

Transferred architectural background skills while learning about Ontario Building Code, LEED, Revit, Construction Estimating and MS Excel, Project Management Principles.

BA. Architecture / Azad University

March 2006 - April 2010, Iran

Evaluated as equivalent to a 4-years Canadian Bachelor's Degree in Architecture by WES.

CERTIFICATES

User Experience Design /

BrainStation

January 2020 - March 2020

Completed a series of workshops and created a mobile app.

User Interface Design /

Red Academy

October 2018 - December 2018

Completed a series of workshops and designed a website.